<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content>
<page>
	<block>Being overweight or obese creates a predisposition to major health risk factors such as hyper-tension, hyperlipidemia, and type 2 diabetes, and is a leading determinant for increased levels of inactivity for an affected individual. Obesity is the condition of being considerably over-weight, and refers to a person with a body mass index (BMI) of 30 or higher or who is at least 30 pounds over the recommended weight for their height (Must et al., 1999). It is a complex condition that increases the risk of death from chronic diseases and is a major cause of prevent-able death (Centers for Disease Control and Prevention [CDC], 2016). In the United States, the occurrence of obesity in the population varies by state and territory. As of 2014, no U.S. state had a prevalence of obesity below 20%, and in three states 35% or more of the populations fell into this high-risk category (CDC, 2014). Overall, the rate of obesity in the United States is high, with approximately one-third of adults and one-fifth of children being classified as obese (Ogden, Kit, & Flegal, 2014).</block>
	<block>In the 1950s, health clubs consisted of bodybuilders, power lifters, Olympic lifters, and athletes. It was a male-dominated environment in which men trained with free weights to increase mus-cle size and strength. Then, in 1951 Jack LaLanne began hosting America’s first televised fitness show, The Jack LaLanne Show, which aired until 1984. Jack’s workouts consisted mainly of cal-isthenics intermixed with tips on counting calories, weight training, and nutrition. Yet before pioneering a TV show, at the age of 21 Jack LaLanne opened his first health club in Oakland, California, in 1936 where he invented the cable pulley weight training system and the Smith weightlifting machine. Today, both of these implements are still actively used in most fitness centers around the world.</block>
	<block></block>
	<block></block>
</page>
</content>